# **SELINA YANG**

0435 511 180

✓ selinayanganlan722@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/selinayangruns

# **SUMMARY**

Core strength with over 3 years of experience being accountable for end-to-end BI development and support of BI reports and dashboards across Local Health Districts in NSW Health, Banking (ICBC) and Finance (MetLife).

Range of experiences from building business cases for BI projects, proof of concepts and prototyping, to large-scale state-wide migration from SAP BusinessObjects to Microsoft Power BI.

Versed in engaging non-technical stakeholders such as Director of Finance, Director of Workforce, Ministry of Health, Surgical Waitlist and Patient Flow Manager at NSW Health, and Investment Bankers/Venture Capitalists in Australia. Maintained strong trusted relationships with Business Analytics Manager, Project Managers and other Business Analysts.

Over the past 12 months, learnt and experienced Microsoft Power Platforms and Robotic Process Automation (RPA) for automating repetitive tasks and building Power Apps with Al Ventures.

Well-known for reliability and consistently delivering with a strong growth-mindset attitude.

# **SKILLS**

- Business Intelligence tools such as Microsoft Power BI, Tableau
- Programming Languages such as SQL, DAX, Python
- Data Warehouse tools such as Microsoft Azure SQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services
- · Business Process Automation using Microsoft Power Automate, Microsoft Power Apps
- Enterprise Applications such as SAP, Salesforce, Microsoft Dynamics 365
- Certified in Agile Project Management
- Well versed in JIRA, Confluence, Azure DevOps

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Southern NSW Local Health District, NSW Health, Sydney Business Intelligence Analyst

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

- Transformed Sybase SQL in SAP to T-SQL in Microsoft SQL Server as part of the migration from SAP BusinessObjects to Microsoft Power BI
- Negotiated with key stakeholders (technical/non-technical), developers, and product owners around what to include with regards to data points and from which departments
- Highly interacted in the daily scrum meetings with NSW Health Business Analytics Manager, translated business requirements from Director of Finance, Director of Workforce and Ministry of Health into technical requirements and solution proposals on Azure DevOps
- Communicated technical issues and challenges, impacts, timelines and rollout plans to non-technical stakeholders such as Surgical Waitlist and Patient Flow Manager and other department managers in a non-technical way
- Developed and monitored KPI Matrix in Power BI by integrating Actual, Target, Prior and Variance over time for Finance, Workforce, Emergency and Surgical Department

# Murrumbidgee Local Health District, NSW Health, Sydney Business Intelligence Analyst

Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

- Led several proof of concepts and prototyping such as developing initial reporting concepts on Power BI before a full-fledged server-side solution
- Collaborated with the team and stakeholders to ensure dashboards and reports meet with NSW Health UI/UX standards, styles, designs, themes and user-friendliness
- Assessed functional and non-functional requirements from NSW Health Business Analytics Manager and implemented Power BI reports to meet both business and technical needs
- Assisted the Data Manager in restructuring and optimising data modelling in Microsoft SQL Server Analysis Services
  (SSAS) for new requirements to incorporate new measures in Executive Management Dashboards

# Al Ventures, Sydney

#### **Business Intelligence Analyst**

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

- Improved HR processes (onboarding, learning and development, performance evaluation and exit process) by 50% by developing Power BI dashboards on top of Microsoft Azure SQL
- Led 2 junior interns to identify HR process improvements and automate repetitive processes using Microsoft Power Automate, resulting in over 10 hours of HR time reduction per week
- Designed and implemented a HR management app using Microsoft Power Apps, improving efficiency and employee engagement by over 80%
- Engaged with business development, sales and marketing stakeholders to formulate business requirements and implement data migration from Microsoft Dynamics 365 to HubSpot
- · Collaborated closely with the Data Analyst team to enable data migration and external data sources

# METASENSE, Sydney

### **Business Intelligence Analyst**

Jul 2019 - Dec 2019

- Led data-driven strategy and insights to support an early-stage medical start-up in the area of UV radiation detection and prevention of skin cancer
- Formulated business requirements and built customer dashboards using Tableau
- Managed end-to-end data collection, data validation and data consolidation from external sources such as LinkedIn and other websites
- Wrote user manuals, conducted workshops and trained 5 internal stakeholders on the usage of HubSpot, data management and reporting

#### **GAOTek**, Sydney

#### **Business Intelligence Analyst**

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

- Analysed e-commerce sales data (Amazon) of optical products and developed visually appealing and interactive dashboards using Tableau
- Wrote Python scripts to automate the extraction of product specification data from supplier websites
- Documented dashboard and report specifications such as data source, data pipeline, ETL process and produced operational support manuals

#### MetLife, China

**Data Analyst** 

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

- Analysed and presented the insights of performance data in the onboarding and first-month for over 40 new hires each month
- Managed and optimized data collection processes such as paper-based attendance form and assessments into digital spreadsheets for analysis and reporting
- Orchestrated training and onboarding for over 150 new hires along with senior management and other trainers, including organizing facilities and events

#### Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC), China

**Data Analyst** 

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

- Analysed and presented the insights to Personal Loan Managers based on lending records and approvals
- Identified potential risks in commercial lending for over 500 credit applications
- Facilitated IT processes such as data backup and documentation for the business lending department

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Master of Commerce (Business Analytics)**

The University of Sydney, Australia

### **Bachelor of Business Management**

The University of Surrey, UK

## CERTIFICATION

- Microsoft Power BI Essentials
- SOL for Data Science
- Agile Project Management
- Stakeholder Management
- Participation of Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Dynamics 365 Fundamentals
- Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals
- Introduction to Microsoft Power Automate
- AWS Cloud Foundation for Businesses